hello my name is greater welcome back to
another episode of hermitcraft and today
i'm going to start off by making some
sweet changes to the bottom layer now
last episode i talked about
the nether portal now i've been
currently using that one over there but
i talked about putting it
right on the top of the base
i even put a card on it to vote on it
and
i've changed my mind basically
in in short i have actually changed my
mind i'm allowed to do that it's okay
and i'm actually going to get rid of
this tube here because i've got one here
and one here also although i've never
actually filled this one up and i'm
gonna put the nether portal right there
now i actually agree with you guys that
the portal ideas up there looked really
cool they looked really really cool
but i realized i would never actually
use it i think i even talked about that
so we're gonna put one here but i also
want to put a little bit of a decoration
over here as well so before we get
started into the meat of today's episode
we're gonna do a little bit of housework
yeah i know you gotta do a bit of chores
every now and again
but at the end of it this place should
start looking a little bit cleaner
and we're going to start off by making a
big g because that's well that's me
and we're going to decorate it slightly
as well
so we've got a big g here and i'm also
going to link it up with some end rods
now that's the best way i could come up
with to light this up as best as i could
because putting torches here as we can
tell in the base it it doesn't look very
good but end rods they kind of work with
the whole theme that i've got going on
here the futuristic theme the only
problem is they are rather expensive to
make
and they don't always fit but for this
particular part of the build i think it
works really well
there we go i think that looks pretty
good the g's all linked up it's got a
nice amount of light around it and
that's the first thing that you're going
to see when you come out of this portal
here you'll just see the giant jeep
although that beacon is totally in the
way but i think it works nonetheless
i do use this funnel here occasionally
but i have a feeling that i will use the
nether portal a whole bunch more than
this and most of the time i fly out of
my base anyway so we've got to take down
this which has actually been here a
really long time this water funnel but i
think once i've got this portal in you
will all agree with me that this was
necessary because if i had to use the
portal that would be all the way up here
that's how long i'd have to use four or
five rockets just to use my nether
portal and i just i can't see that
happening and plus i kind of like the
way that it looks here where there's
nothing there it kind of gives it a
little bit more height i feel
so yeah and i also played around with a
few ideas to
decorate these bits but most of those
failed as well so i'm not going to try
and force anything that's the main thing
with this base i got to let it come
naturally this this second ring that
came naturally and i think it looks
really cool
but for the top and i think i'm going to
leave it for now and decorating all this
bit i'm going to leave it for now as
well but i also if you didn't notice
spent a lot of time singing pickles on
the seafloor and i have lit up most of
this area it's amazing what pickles can
do to make the underwater scene look
absolutely magnificent so i'm going to
basically continue lighting this up for
as long as i can be bothered and see
what that looks like i've cleaned out
this area now and i'm going to make
where the portal is going to go
so that's where the portal is going to
go but obviously that's not very well
decorated and i am basically not i'm not
going to turn this on because it's going
to be so loud
but i'm going to try and decorate it the
best i can
so i think i'm going to put like a
framework around it because it's so
inset i think this could work really
well but also try and make it connect up
to what i've already got here
well where did you come from
what the heck
[Music]
oh
goodness i also just realized
that's not even in line
that is so wonky how did i miss that
there we go
that's fixed that up that's much better
i can't believe i didn't see that okay
let's focus on this i like where it's
going
but
it
making this work at the top this
decoration thing isn't going so well but
i think it could also do
with an architect logo if i'm being
honest so make a big a-frame out of
quartz
and then we take some slabs and i think
we connect up
i think i did something wrong here i
think
oh wow
you know haste is so good at the same
time it's so annoying
i think you connect up these ones and
replace
this
like that i believe that is how it's
done i think we've got a pretty good
looking portal there actually this could
work well now this kind of abruptly
stops and that's not very good looking
unless i remove that
or i could bring it round with another
layer but i don't really want to have to
do another layer all the way around so
maybe just this side i don't know maybe
let's take a look what that looks like
or i'm just creating even more ledges
for the mobs to spawn on making my
my base has kind of been mob free for a
while
but as i keep building
they keep coming back
there we go that looks pretty decent i
must admit
now all they're left is to do
is to actually light it
now where do i look at this mess i can't
find anything here ever
oh there we go flint's i will find it
it's an organized mess
but look how much i've collected here
just sand sand terracotta gravel gravel
gravel gravel
like there's just so much stuff here
i've been really grinding away all right
three
two one it's like the christmas lights
boom
and we have our new portal i think that
that looks pretty good i really do need
to put something up in between those
but other than that i think that looks
really nice
it makes it look way more official now
if you got rid of all the rubbish that
i've got on each side i think that would
look even better
i think we should start considering that
i need to clean up it's like i haven't
tidied my bedroom for like four months
time to get rid of this little portal
here because we now have an official one
all right i got some sea lanterns we're
going in
ow okay i was trying to place that and
fly away
there we go
that has placed the sea lantern exactly
where it needs to be
and that's it pretty much i could put
the sea lantern here
where
the other one is like there we go i
think that looks pretty decent actually
i won't complain at all i think that
this stuff needs cleaning up though i'm
really happy with that i think that has
improved the base a lot
i do need to clean up the rest of this
place but uh we'll get to that
eventually i can probably start with all
these pumpkins to be fair
and we're gonna set jack skelebone free
as well i think he should be allowed to
roam around as he pleases i don't think
he can escape or get stuck but
i haven't really been using him a lot so
i think he should at least be allowed to
free roam
now that we've done some house chores we
can get on with some of the things that
we really need to do today and it does
include a bit more building but one of
those things is that someone where have
i put them i've lost my heads again no
here they are all right
don't you hate it when you just lose
your head constantly right so i have got
another stack and a bit of green heads
but instead of just placing them around
on the server i thought i could do sort
of a special kind of event i'm going to
hide a big green head somewhere in the
world and i'm going to fill it to the
brim with some of these heads that i've
got
ah now i remember why you were put away
you like to stand exactly where i need
to be he's like a cat he has to stand on
the keyboard now obviously i can't show
you where i'm going to go on camera but
hopefully when i'm there you won't be
able to recognize it
now why on earth has scar
putting this here why is there a random
floating nether quartz
what is this about i kind of want to get
rid of it but i also want to know what
this is about
all right let's go and find a place as
you can see i've already placed a few
and i'm gonna leave some hints or
riddles about where they might be
clearly wherever i'm hiding it it's
definitely underground but i could
genuinely be anywhere on the server
right now and that's the whole point you
guys have a bad habit of letting the
other hermits know where stuff is
because you want to see them
understandably you want to see them do
whatever it is that i've set up but this
time it's a secret so i'm gonna hide
maybe 20 or 30 green heads in this one
location and i'm gonna leave a riddle if
you can figure out the riddle by
yourself then by all means tell the
other hermits
unfortunately this means digging out a
very big hole without a beacon and i'm
starting to realize quite how much i
rely on my beacon
and of course i've got to build a giant
green head so that they know that they
found the right place so i think the
best way to do this was to try and build
it as i was going along okay that's what
i'm going to do this since this is only
temporary i'm not going to spend too
much time on it but we are going to put
a bunch of green heads here so that this
is a decent prize for anyone and this
could be the difference between winning
the game and losing the game so that's
about 20 green heads here
and they would have to work to find
where this is now it's time to leave a
riddle back
in the shopping district so people have
a chance to find it
and while i'm at it i might as well
place a few more green heads because
i've got a few left over
so i've done one of my riddles hopefully
people will figure this out i think this
one is personally the easiest one and i
think a lot of you will immediately get
it so green head riddle inside the
spherical bone that leaves redstone you
will need to go inside the cutlery that
sits above the plate with pride all
right hopefully that makes sense now
let's go and make another one real quick
no i'm i'm writing the riddle why are
you here
go
you know what
scars shop is an absolute death trap
scar how many times have i said to you
light this place up
it's an absolute nightmare
honestly
now this is where i left my underground
one so the green head riddle from night
to day but never day to night seek
beneath the tower of fright
now
i hope that that is vague enough for
people to figure out maybe or maybe it's
too vague
it's probably not the best riddle in the
world but if you can figure it out
it will be worth something
i'm gonna keep the rest of these green
heads i think maybe place a couple more
here or there but other than that i
think i'm gonna keep these in case i
want to make another little green riddle
depends how easily people find it if
people find those green heads i've left
two locations with a decent amount of
green heads in them now if the hermits
figure out where they are within a
couple of days i'm gonna give away these
17 of them in a way more difficult
riddle i'm not very good at coming up
with riddles but i thought it would be a
fun way instead of just
putting them around everywhere and
hoping that everyone finds them and as i
talked about this before i've come up
with the greatest plan for this area and
oh my goodness is it still a mess in
here but i think that's what we're going
to time lapse now but
i don't think that i'm going to tell you
exactly what i'm up to because this is
kind of a long-term project
but it's not my project you have to
understand that it's not my project
it's the man in the chicken
costume all right let's get into it i'm
afraid that this time lapse might be a
little bit on the disappointing side and
i'm gonna keep it very very short just
one minute long and one minute is not
very long at all considering this was
three hours of work that you're about to
see well not even three hours look
listen this was like the biggest fail
not only did i forget to press f1 so you
can see the chat
but my laptop wasn't plugged in properly
into the power socket and so
it ran out of battery halfway through so
i'm like turning around and i see it
going bidding and i'm like no
i'm frantically trying to plug it back
in and it was too late it had gone dead
and i lost about an hour and a half's
worth of footage but as you can see i am
slowly turning this cave
into a cave i know right very creative
so this box that was a total mess this
hole that i haven't had anything to do
with for a while i'm going to turn it
into a very man-made cave so it will
look quite ovular in shape but when i'm
finished well the thing is i didn't
actually finish because it took so long
to make and i really wanted to get this
video finished so i kind of had to cut
it short and it's okay i will be able to
do these sorts of things in various
parts and there's even more bad news
unfortunately i didn't have enough time
to finish the whole time lapse but as
you can see i've made some pretty decent
progress now what i've done here is not
how it might look when it's going to be
finished but i've got a very basic shape
to this cave
i need to put a load of staircases slabs
and details in and the shape's not quite
finished especially in the corners all
of those bits where you have to go
really high up man i seriously kind of
regret this now because this is such a
large project i was time lapsing for
maybe two or three hours
and i really thought i would finish by
now but if i want to get this video out
i've got to cut this one short so we'll
continue this little time lapse
in the next episode because this is
critical i can't express enough how
important this room is but i've also got
some pretty terrible news everybody
just after i stopped recording to make
that time lapse i have this annoying
habit when i play hermitcraft
as soon as i stop recording i hit the
off and then i go and tab out and press
all my do hickory jigs to stop
everything recording and then i forget
to log out okay
and this happened just after i said
let's go do that time lapse and i came
back and i was gone
i had died to a zombie because i forgot
to log out
and so
i lost everything no i mean everything i
lost my helmet elytra
trousers and i had to spend an hour and
a half nearly two hours getting
everything back but i took that
opportunity to really try and buff up my
stuff again
but oh goodness
if you've ever lost all your stuff in
minecraft
you know how annoying it is
but i've got some pretty decent stuff
now i could probably do a bit more but
my boots in particular
and i got i've now actually renamed
everything so
this is the gs machine and the gs is the
gravel and sand machine because that's
basically what i use it for i upgraded
that to efficiency 5 fax machine backup
back in action exactly the same as it
was and sword i was feeling i'm not
gonna lie i was feeling so down-hearted
after losing everything i didn't even
have a good name for my sword so it's
just called sword and then i got the axe
machine which is a pun on the fax
machine and i haven't actually finished
enchanting that one again but then i got
the silk machine which is slightly
better than the other one so yeah i've
got all my stuff back now but
do you know what's really weird
mumbo also lost all of his gear because
he was killed by a phantom while he was
afk architects and afk is not a good
idea
but he's pretty bummed out because he
lost something that he couldn't replace
and that was a trident not just any
trident his riptide trident that he was
ripping on quite a lot so i've got one
for him here i had a load of spare trims
because i've been really lucky with them
and i've enchanted it all up and i've
renamed it
it is called the fork of friendship and
i'm going to give it to him and he is
currently afk
as you might expect
he's even made an extra layer of
protection so mumbo lost his stuff
because he made a box that looked like
this and the phantoms spawned in their
millions and then they went through here
and managed to damage him through the
whole box
so i think the only logical thing here
is to
i mean mumbo if you're gonna go fk
you know he's even put a he's even put a
chest with all his stuff on it
so yeah you know if you go afk mumbo i'm
gonna mess with you and i think he's afk
because he has made
a pretty nifty creeper farm so how is it
doing
oh wow yep that's a fair amount of
gunpowder i am enjoying that okay mumbo
uh i've trapped myself in here with you
and i'm gonna leave the fork of
friendship right there but i kind of
want to leave a sign for you no wait i
don't even need to leave a sign i'll
just leave a green head there he's gonna
know maybe
maybe i should make it very clear
who left this
there we go yep i think that's very
clear who left this in here i really
hope that mumbo goes afk here again for
longer because oh boy if he does this
often because of the gunpowder thing oh
i'm totally gonna mess with him all the
time
well that was a nice deed that i did and
i'm hoping that he hasn't already got
himself a riptide trident because i did
go through the effort of getting that
for him
man when you lose your stuff it is not
fun at all
and there's a random nether portal
that's appeared
on my giant ring where does this go to
wait
this goes to my nether portal the heck
something's not right here well this
goes back to my base man the nether's so
confusing what's going on
so does this one take me back exactly
there what the heck
okay maybe there's another portal hidden
somewhere that someone used
no
maybe this one
where does this portal go
well this is mumbo's portal
how the heck have we got a mysterious
portal arriving here that makes no sense
oh
i said i see you are using the system as
well
this is so strange there must be a rogue
portal somewhere
there absolutely must be
well this doesn't make much sense at all
all right well i guess we'll just get
rid of it we'll never understand the
mystery of the portal
so anyway that's it for today's episode
i'm afraid everybody i lost all my gear
i have tidied up the base a little bit i
even got rid of that when all this is
clear imagine how nice this is gonna
look i've added a new nether portal
right here which is somewhat of a
downgrade from the plans that i had up
there but i think this is gonna be used
a little bit more we did a gigantic time
lapse of the little cave down there and
we set up a couple of green head riddles
actually speaking of which has anyone
donated more gems
oh legends
okay the green head hunt continues
everyone i feel like i need to
constantly be adding green heads into
the system
or the game will just slow down a lot
now i don't know what's going on in the
background but i think some dodgy
dealings are happening and as far as i'm
aware that it's all fair game to be
honest
oh okay yeah we got the we got one
riddle here and we got one riddle there
i don't know if anyone's found them
but we are going to go and add a few
more heads to the game and that's it for
today so thank you very much for
watching everyone i hope you enjoyed
this episode and i hope you're going to
look forward to the secrets of the new
cave that i'm going to be making
so our feathered friend may make a
return
thank you very much for watching
everyone and good
bye